<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Casper Andersson</title><link>https://casan.se/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Casper Andersson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://casan.se/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hexend - Send raw hex frames</title><link>https://casan.se/blog/hexend-send-raw-hex-frames/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casan.se/blog/hexend-send-raw-hex-frames/</guid><description>In my daily work I sometimes want to copy and modify raw frames as hexdumps. I will usually copy a hexdump from Wireshark or Tcpdump. Some times I have, however, written frames from scratch. Not very complex ones; nevertheless, it is nice to have the possibility to.
There are plenty of tools out there for building and sending frames.</description></item><item><title>The day Make started crashing</title><link>https://casan.se/blog/the-day-make-started-crashing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casan.se/blog/the-day-make-started-crashing/</guid><description>This is a short story from $DAYJOB about my discovery and investigations of an issue with the build system.
One day when building our code I suddenly got a segmentation fault when building. An odd occurrence. I could not recall any changes to the build system and checking the Git log I could not find any changes that would affect it.</description></item><item><title>A simpler life without sudo</title><link>https://casan.se/blog/a-simpler-life-without-sudo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casan.se/blog/a-simpler-life-without-sudo/</guid><description>A couple months ago a colleague showed me his post on a life without sudo. In it he demonstrates the elegant use of Linux capabilities(7). If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with capabilities I recommend reading his post first. I started using it myself and found it incredibly convenient. I would run sudo many times per day before.</description></item><item><title>Network bridge forwarding and learning</title><link>https://casan.se/blog/network-bridge-forwarding-and-learning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casan.se/blog/network-bridge-forwarding-and-learning/</guid><description>A network switch has multiple ports to send and receive data on. To manage this there is a component called &amp;ldquo;bridge&amp;rdquo; inside it. In Linux the bridge is defined as a network interface, but it it can also be offloaded to hardware (at least parts of it). The bridge is responsible for connecting different networks with each other.</description></item><item><title>Bouncing balls simulation using X11</title><link>https://casan.se/blog/bouncing-balls-simulation-using-x11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://casan.se/blog/bouncing-balls-simulation-using-x11/</guid><description>Recently I got the idea that I wanted to experiment with using X11 directly, instead of some higher-level library where buttons and fields already exist as objects. The goal was to get a better idea of how the graphics and window systems works in Linux (X11 specifically). This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a huge project and I only got to see parts of it before moving on, but it was a very interesting experience.</description></item></channel></rss>